[gunshot]
♪ Take a little walk
To the edge of town ♪
♪ And go across the tracks ♪
♪ Where the viaduct looms ♪
♪ Like a bird of doom ♪
♪ As it shifts and cracks ♪
♪ Where secrets lie
In the border fires ♪
♪ In the humming wires ♪
♪ Hey man, you know ♪
♪ You're never coming back ♪
♪ Past the square
Past the bridge ♪
♪ Past the mills
Past the stacks ♪
♪ On a gathering storm comes ♪
♪ A tall handsome man ♪
♪ In a dusty black coat with ♪
♪ A red right hand ♪
[Arthur] Watch out, John-Boy,
he has got a strong left.
-[Tommy] Arthur, John, Finn. Come here.
-[indistinct chatter]
[horse neighs]
[Arthur] All right, what is it?
This letter says that Dad's dead.
He was in Boston
in a bar called the Mickey Free.
Two men waiting in an alley.
He was shot twice.
Who's Rosie Rice?
Some fucking whore.
She is a woman
who took the trouble to write to us.
And she wanted us to know
that during the night,
while he was dying,
he asked for our forgiveness.
The only thing he ever taught us
was how to kill and cut a stag.
-Finn, John, you won't remember.
-I remember. Cannock Chase.
Parked up at a pub called the Griffin.
He got drunk and sang "Silver Dagger"
about 100 times.
Yeah. One weekend.
One weekend he was like that.
[Tommy] The stag is to remember him.
We eat and then we forget him.
No need to forgive him. Agreed?
John, I have to say this.
You can name your new baby after him
if you like.
No.
Arthur, and I won't even ask.
So his name dies.
It's been in the family for a long time,
but now it's gone.
All right, that's done. Fuck him.
Before we cook and eat,
there's some business.
Boys!
I wanted to say this out here, 'cause
I don't trust the maids in the house.
There's gonna be a robbery.
-I wish to confess.
-There's no confessional today.
The name's Shelby.
-[creaking]
-[door closes]
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
Today is a holy day.
Look, I came. I made myself.
You been drinking?
I couldn't sleep.
I tried to get enough down me
to get myself to sleep, but...
I just do these night vigils
by myself, thinking...
How long since your last confession?
I don't remember.
Mrs. Shelby,
do you have something to confess?
Do you know it is actually "Gray"?
My name is, um, Elizabeth Gray.
Yeah. Do you think God calls me
Pol or Polly?
Voice calls me Pol.
You hear a voice?
-Yeah. Like Bernadette heard a voice.
-And what does the voice say?
"Murderer."
It says this to you?
It's in my head.
Who else would it be talking to?
And are you a murderer?
If you're talking about the law, then...
[footsteps approach]
-Yes.
-[knocking on door]
-I'll be out in a moment, Peter.
-[Peter] Yes, Father.
[footsteps fading]
Are you saying
you want to confess to a murder?
[Polly] No.
My confession is that I feel no regret.
He was a policeman,
he was a bad man, he hurt me.
I do the things I do
so that my son doesn't have to do them.
It's just the wiping away of the shit
from under your feet.
The taking of any human life
is a mortal sin.
No, the unjust taking of a human life
Look it up. Look who did it.
Moses, Samson, Lord Kitchener.
Are you saying
you took the life of a policeman?
[Polly sighs]
[creaking]
Oh, Father.
[sobbing]
Now there is another life to be taken.
If there is a voice telling you
to take a life, you must ignore it.
The voice doesn't tell me.
The voice asks me.
It says, "Pol,
does this way of excusing
a murder still work
if the life that is going to be taken
is a consecrated man?"
He's a man of the cloth.
He's a holy man.
What kind of holy man?
[sighing]
[door opens]
[footsteps fading]
[door closes]
-[Esme] It's not fair.
-[door opens]
They're off drinking and shooting rifles
as we sit here.
-[door closes]
-Listen to the mugs swearing,
spitting on the bloody floor
for us to fucking wipe up!
Without men here,
they'd be like dogs pissing up the wall.
I was just saying it's not fair.
The men are down there like lords.
Esme, just...
Get on with it.
I'm bloody five months gone.
[sniffing]
-[sighs] Forgot the combination.
-24-8-22.
How do you know
the paper cash combination?
-Tommy talks in his sleep.
-Shut up, Esme.
[clanks]
[groans]
He's changed the combination.
-[Lizzie] You've put it in wrong.
-No, I haven't.
Your hands are shaking.
[creaks]
[sniffing]
And actually, I am sleeping with Tommy,
okay? Now and then.
Because he wants to, now and then.
When the mood takes him.
Except we don't sleep. It's hard to sleep
bent over a desk, isn't it?
Happy?
-[door opens]
-[women talking indistinctly]
None of it's fucking fair.
[Tommy] It's two hours' work.
Bit of grease on your cuffs,
and that's it.
Tommy, should I really be here for this?
I've cleared it with Polly, Michael.
There's no way around it.
We need you to know.
Who the fuck wants to buy
27 stolen armored cars?
A foolish man.
[Michael] And how much
is this foolish man paying?
£150,000. Cash, diamonds and sapphires.
So that's 20 for you, Charlie.
Isiah, there's 5 to you.
The rest we take to America
to invest in legally-acquired property.
Assets bought
with untraceable income resold,
and the profits reinvested
to make sure it's clean.
[Arthur] And after that, I suppose,
the whole business will be like that stag
hanging up over there, right, Tom?
Well, with profits on this scale,
we'll be in a position
to stop the off-track business for good.
Keep the pubs, stop the protection.
Horses for the sport
and race days for a lark.
I made a promise to Charles' mother.
Now, I also made a promise to Linda.
I know.
I can see it in your eyes, man.
Part of the reason for doing this last job
is so you'll be set up
when you do decide to walk away.
[Strong] Look at you, Arthur.
A man that wanted to live a clean life,
but here you are signing up for
the biggest robbery of all.
I have to hand it to you, Tom.
-You're a smart man.
-You in or out, Charlie?
Curly?
Shouldn't have killed the stag, Tommy.
-Oh, shut up. Shut up.
-Bad luck.
How do we know this foolish man will
hand over the diamonds when we're done?
We don't.
But that's another business.
Right, let's cook some meat.
[banging on door]
[Esme] Can't wait to part
with their money, stupid bastards.
[Linda] It's all right, it's me.
[door closes]
Arthur said you'd be short-staffed today
because they are on a works outing.
[Esme] Piss-up, actually.
I brought sandwiches
and this lemonade I made myself.
[typewriter keys clacking]
I'll make tea and empty ashtrays,
but I won't handle money or slips.
Arthur says what you do here
is illegal, but not immoral.
[Esme] Depends what time
you get here, Linda.
And anyway,
I thought I'd offer you my physical and
spiritual support in your time of need.
Oh, Linda, if you want to be a help,
run up to the shops
and get me 20 Senior Service.
-Lizzie'll give you the change.
-[chuckles] No, I won't.
Actually, I'll use my own money, Polly.
And before you ladies decide to find me
so amusing, I have a message for you.
Oh, God, no, Linda.
I've been to church already. Have you?
It's not a message from God, Polly.
-It's from Jessie Eden.
-Who's Jessie Eden?
[Linda] She's the lady shop steward
at the Lucas factory in Sparkhill.
[Esme] Lady shop steward?
She's bringing all the female workers
in the spot-welding and wire-cutting shops
out on strike for the day.
In protest at being made to work
on a holy day.
Poor conditions, lack of holidays,
unsanitary lavatory provisions
and lower pay for female workers.
Apparently, all the female
factory workers in the city
are joining the protest in sympathy
and will walk out of their places of work
at 9:00 a.m.
-to march on the Bull Ring.
-[banging on door]
All oppressed female workers welcome.
Them bastards down there shooting deer.
Me five months gone,
sat here like a pudding.
[Linda] Only one outside lavatory
between the lot of us.
Not consulted.
-Bent over a fucking desk.
-[banging continues]
Ladies, I honestly believe those who march
on Good Friday have God on their side.
-[banging on door]
-[man] It's 9 o'clock, ladies!
Open the fucking door!
Fuck it.
I'm not in the mood today.
Let's go to the Bull Ring.
Hallelujah!
[rock music playing]
[whistle blows]
[Michael] The foolish man?
Not quite.
I'm sorry I came unannounced.
What do you want?
We need proof.
Proof of what? [clears throat]
You said the priest is a traitor.
We need to know how you know.
The proof is my word.
If he is involved, I'm out.
He needs to die.
Are you always so violent?
I killed a stag today,
and it hurt me to do it.
But I treated it with respect,
and the spare meat will go to poor people.
It will grieve me far less
to put a bullet in the priest's face.
Will you not sit when a duchess sits?
I'm told you're part of the deal.
Is that true?
The Royal Court in Tbilisi
actually worked very efficiently.
Ah, I see. And it worked like this, eh?
[Tatiana] There were lots of corridors
and small rooms.
Attics.
There were no rules there.
Deals were done.
Brothers gave sisters, aunts gave uncles,
fathers gave daughters and servants.
[glass clinks]
It was my aunt's idea that I came alone.
She is in charge of this.
When there are no rules,
women take charge.
They understand that the power they have
comes through silent agreements.
I've promised I will do everything I can
to make this plan work.
My aunt assumed you would want me
as part of the deal.
I will tell her she's wrong.
-[footsteps approach]
-[door opens]
[chuckling]
Tommy, you ain't gonna believe this, man.
I just phoned the garrison, right?
I just spoke to Billy.
He says Polly, Esme and Lizzie have
gone on fucking strike.
[laughs]
-They what?
-They've gone on fucking strike!
Half of Birmingham is out.
The female half, they're all out,
every single one of them.
Quakers put 'em up to it.
Who's watching the shop?
[John] Polly's locked it up.
See, Good Friday's
one of our best days for takings.
All the men get drunk.
The races are all fixed.
It's like picking apples
off the lowest branches.
Hey, John?
Hmm, yes.
Then your business is very easy.
-Was Linda with them?
-You know,
Billy said that Polly jumped
in the fucking Bull Ring,
just pissed out of her mind,
started going on about revolution,
screaming to the rooftops.
Was Linda with them?
Yeah.
Then it was Linda's idea.
-Linda's a smart woman.
-[footsteps approach]
John.
There's a Bentley in the drive outside.
I want you to go out
and put a nail in its tire.
It's Good Friday,
so there'll be no garages open.
The lady will have to spend the night.
Then I want you and the boys
to all go home.
You take Charlie, put him with
Arthur and Linda for the night.
They can use the practice.
-You want to put a nail...
-Yeah.
-You heard me.
Right. Nice to meet you.
Why do you need to put a nail in the tire?
I want it so neither of us
can change our minds.
[creaking]
[clanking]
[John] We came back early.
Polly didn't finish the count yesterday.
Hmm.
So you thought you could take a tenner.
I thought I'd finish the count.
[both grunting]
[John] Hey!
Esme, I've told you.
Stay off the snow until the baby's born.
[Esme] It does no harm, passes the time.
-Knocks down the walls.
-Listen. [grunts]
[panting] Listen.
I know you miss the traveling.
It's all gonna be all right.
It's like being a hen in a coop.
Remember that house in Lichfield?
The one the bailiff
used to throw you out of?
Throw you in a ditch.
I'm gonna buy that fucking house.
Big as Tommy's and more land.
If you feel cooped up,
we'll take a wagon, camp out by the ditch.
How?
[sniffles]
It's all gonna change, Esme.
[Tatiana] This is not your bedroom.
This is not where
you slept with your wife.
Do you ride horses?
No.
I would need to open my legs in
a public place, and that is not allowed.
You drink whiskey?
No.
It tastes like men. I prefer wine.
Cars?
No.
So, diamonds are your only love, eh?
-Sapphires?
-[chuckles]
They're just a currency.
Well, you know,
if it was me who had all them jewels,
I think I'd just sit with them,
look at them,
touch them.
Izabella does that sometimes.
Late at night.
I swear she puts one of the biggest
sapphires into her body for pleasure,
and walks up the stairs
to breakfast with it still in place.
[laughs]
-And it stays in there all day?
-Yeah.
Oh.
What is your weakness?
Talking about duchesses
with sapphires inside of them.
Mmm.
I think I already know your weakness.
I can get a fuck whenever I want, love.
Yes.
But I am a duchess.
And I am under you like a horse.
-I'm like a telegram.
-[chuckling]
"A telegram"?
I don't think your English is so good.
Or maybe you should listen more carefully
to what I have to say.
Hmm?
I have a message for you, Mr. Shelby.
As a duchess, I can show you
what is possible for a man like you.
A man in a house like this.
Right now, you hide inside it like a boy
who's broken in through the window.
Why did we come to a bedroom for this?
Hmm?
In your own house?
[door opens]
-[Tatiana laughs]
-It's a loaded fucking weapon.
We could fuck by the fire with the maids
standing to attention and watching, huh?
What can they do?
-Give it here.
-Nothing.
There are no rules for you. Hmm?
Give me the fucking gun.
You have maids here.
You can bring a maid into the room.
What can I do about that? Nothing.
-Give me the fucking gun, now.
-You have power.
Everyone does what you tell them to do.
Your brothers, your soldiers,
no one can stop you.
Don't point the fucking weapon at me.
I can be an actress.
Who do you want me to be?
Your dead wife?
Now, that's enough.
Give me the fucking gun!
If you don't like something,
you say stop, and it stops. Hmm?
But you are afraid of it.
You break the law,
but you obey the rules. Why?
Did you know that madness sets you free?
Otherwise, we're just peasants
obeying the law.
There is madness inside your head, too.
I can see that.
Let a duchess show you something.
[footsteps thudding]
[door opens]
[clicking]
[gun barrel turns]
I emptied the chamber,
except for one bullet.
-No! No, please.
-This is a game we used to play.
No.
-Watch.
-Do not fucking do this.
No. Look at me.
Don't do this.
-[clicks]
-No!
Give me the fucking thing.
It brings you alive. You won't try it?
No, I do not want to try!
And I do not want your mad fucking
Russian brains all over me fucking walls.
I survive each time by the will of God.
Get to fucking bed, now!
[Tatiana] I already called a maid.
[Tommy] Fucking...
[footsteps thudding]
You see?
You are afraid.
Like a boy who's broken in
through the window.
I need to educate you
in how to run a house like this.
[footsteps approach]
Yes. Come down.
Pour us a drink.
Mary, go back to bed, please.
You go back to bed, please.
This woman is drunk.
That's all right, sir.
Should I pour whiskey?
-Yes, he will have whiskey.
-No, go back to bed.
He will have whiskey and I will have wine!
-Mary, go back to bed.
-[Tatiana] There.
-In an old house like this...
-[Tommy] Stop fucking talking.
-...the servants expect it.
-Mary, go back to bed! Do as I say!
Normally, if there's a call
after midnight,
the maid who comes in
is the one in love with the master,
-but she is not in love with you.
-This is not fucking Russia!
[softly] Please, Mary.
Go back to bed, hey?
I know your weakness, Tommy.
It's freedom.
Madness.
Killing.
I am the first one who understands you.
[footsteps thudding]
I found her perfume.
Put it on.
What proof do you have
that the priest is a spy?
I told you. I give you my word.
Then kill him.
From now on, you must do
everything that you want to do.
There'll be two of us for breakfast
this morning, Mary.
She's gone for a walk by the river.
-[Mary] The lady left, sir.
-[cutlery clinks]
Left? How?
She took your car.
She what?
She was in a terrible hurry.
She said she had your permission.
She told David to go to the garage
to get a new tire for the Bentley.
She said you could use that.
And why the hell would you listen to her?
The way she said it, sir.
[door closes]
-[Arthur] How was she, Tom?
-Talkative, yeah.
Hmm.
I was fucking working, all right?
Yeah.
From what she said,
when she was out of her fucking mind,
I'm pretty certain
the treasury is underneath the house.
What have you got?
Our Ada got this from the British Library
using her scholar's pass.
[Tommy] She talks about her aunt
coming up the stairs
to have breakfast in the morning,
which means
it has to be in the building somewhere.
[Arthur] Wine cellar. Septic.
Kitchen cellar.
[John] And a tunnel under the river.
They don't trust a soul in this country,
so my guess is they've turned
one of the cellars into a strong room.
Did you find someone, Arthur?
Moss got me this.
Stefan Radischevsky.
He's a kid from Greet,
lives in Cheltenham.
Dad's a Russian. He has dreams of
owning a pub, but he's got a record.
-Breaking and entering.
-[Arthur] Hmm.
-And he speaks Russian?
-Yeah.
Their butler drinks in a pub
called the Masons Arms.
Get to him, tell him who we are,
offer him some money
if he gives the kid a job in the house.
-[knocking on door]
-Wait.
Talk to the kid,
offer him one of the pubs
we took off the Italians
if he works in the house for four weeks,
keeps his ears open.
All right?
Come.
The executive committee of
the union of bookies and allied trades
will see you now, sir.
[indistinct chatter]
I heard you were giving speeches
off the back of a wagon, Pol.
I can't remember a fucking thing.
Well, Moss tells me you were threatening
to burn down the town hall.
Oh, Tommy, we were having a laugh.
You know, actually,
the crowd around me was bigger
than the crowd around Jessie Eden.
[Tommy] Who's Jessie Eden?
[Polly] She's too soft.
You're not gonna
break the capitalist system
talking about
separate lavatories for women.
Who is Jessie Eden?
She's a new best friend.
Shop steward at the Lucas factory.
A woman shop steward, I've heard of her.
There is a leaflet here
if you want to take a look, Tommy.
[Lizzie clears throat]
So, separate lavatory?
Is that it? Is that what you want?
I don't know what you want.
You have to tell me what it is
that you want and then I'll know.
Actually, we want to know
about the robbery you're planning.
Not the factory robbery. The other one.
The one you're not
telling the women about.
-John has a big mouth.
-[Esme] No.
Arthur's got a big mouth.
Arthur told Linda, Linda told me.
-Polly?
-Read the leaflet, Tommy.
Ladies, why don't I
talk to Tommy privately,
and then I'll report
back to you faithfully.
You're not just gonna take payment
from the Russians, are you, Tommy?
You're going to clean them out,
is that right?
[Lizzie] Esme?
So, what happens after,
when they come for us?
When I'm about to give birth?
Get out, get back to work.
Esme, come on.
-Keep us posted, won't you, sister?
-I will.
[door closes]
Fucking hell.
So Arthur tells Linda everything, eh?
She's stolen his soul
and taken it to a better place.
The suburbs.
Where men are honest with their wives.
We can trust Lizzie.
Yeah, but I can't trust Esme.
I can't trust the fucking Russians
to pay me what they owe me,
and I can't trust my own brother
to keep his fucking mouth shut.
Did you make progress last night?
Yes.
John said the girl looks like
Edna Purviance from the pictures.
[clicks tongue] Be careful.
She's an excellent source of information
regarding the location of the merchandise.
-Here we go.
-You know,
there is a general lack of discipline
in this fucking company.
She stayed the night.
I'm working, Pol.
I am working for the good of the company.
You're grieving.
And when you grieve,
you make bad choices.
I know. I did it myself.
Look. No more marches.
No more fucking politics.
It can kill us. All right?
Joke or no joke.
Did you tell Arthur about the priest?
I only told you.
Thanks for the burden.
[bell tolling]
You were correct
not to talk over the phone.
What did she say?
She said there was gonna be a killing.
A holy man.
And she was with the Shelbys, was she?
[sighs]
I suppose you have something to say
about yesterday.
No.
It's something else, actually.
I believe Arthur has told you
about some business we're planning, Linda.
Oh, there's always business, Thomas.
And Arthur believes when
this business is done, it'll all be over.
Arthur believes you, but I don't.
[sighs]
Linda, the people who have hired us
to rob the factory are very bad people.
They'll not pay us, as they've promised.
So, on the night of the robbery, we will
take what is ours from their treasury.
And a bit more on top for luck.
If you're saying you're gonna stop Arthur,
I need to know.
That'll be Arthur's decision.
And your plan is still to reform him, eh?
-To the absolute degree of redemption.
-Mmm-hmm.
Well, Arthur will walk away from this
with £30,000. We made a deal.
And afterwards,
you and Arthur can begin your new life.
Did you say 30,000?
Arthur said the estimated total proceeds
would be 150,000.
-Estimated. Yes.
-A third of 150 is 50.
-Why a third?
-The three brothers.
-Finn is not yet a man.
-There are expenses.
Of 25,000, you said.
As of last night, the expenses increased.
We need to dig a hole.
Arthur agreed to a plan
with a figure of 25.
25 from 150 is 125.
A third of that is £41,000.
[scoffs]
Sugar?
Yes.
[crockery clinking]
Thank you.
[Tommy clears throat]
So, you've worked this all out, I see?
Only in my head.
I haven't written it down.
Linda, are you saying...
if it were 41,000--
I've already told you,
that'll be Arthur's decision.
But I don't imagine
he'll accept less than 41.
-May I smoke?
-No.
So, I imagine you have some plans
for your 41,000.
Yes. California.
For the child's health,
away from the smoke.
We want to run a general store
on an Indian mission.
The Americans invite Quakers
to do good work with the Indians.
We've already sent our papers
and been accepted.
[chuckles]
Arthur Shelby as a missionary...
-No. Arthur will run the store.
-Hmm.
I will teach in the school next to it.
Arthur will swim in the ocean.
I will be on the beach with the towel.
The open air and the sun will get rid of
all the nonsense in his head from France.
That's some plan.
As you know yourself,
the arrival of a new life
concentrates the mind on practical things.
Amen to that.
When is the child due?
September.
When is the robbery?
June.
Then the timing's perfect.
We'll book a passage
through the Panama Canal
the day after
the 41,000 is paid to Arthur.
[coughing]
Did we agree 41,000, Linda?
I heard nothing to the contrary.
-[Ruben] Word association. Right now.
-Oh, God. I hate this game.
It's Freud. It's terribly fashionable.
I'd rather you put on
that music that I hate.
[sighs] Are we going mad
in here, do you think?
Yes.
[chuckles] We shouldn't have drunk
red wine with the cake.
And I believe your vow never to sleep
with another man is a good one.
Good for the painting.
It's not a vow. It's just...
I think when men want sex,
they become hilarious.
Like a dog, when you pick up a lead,
and he knows he's going for a walk.
Well, may I respectfully point out
that so far you haven't even
picked up the bloody lead.
There.
That's the look.
Imperious.
No man is good enough.
[children talking]
-[roars]
-[all screaming]
[indistinct chatter]
[water dripping]
[grunting]
[both grunting]
[screaming]
[crack]
[thud]
[engine idling]
[inhales sharply]
[Jarvis] You idiot. You nearly killed him.
I told you we needed him fully conscious.
We need to stop using soldiers
who've been in India, they hit too hard.
[Hughes] Not fucking hard enough.
Hey, Mr. Shelby. Hey.
I heard about your plan to kill a holy man
from a voice in the confessional.
[Jarvis] Can you hear us?
[groans]
Grace?
Shelby.
Why were you attempting
to kill Father Hughes?
Maybe we should wait
until he is fully conscious.
I have a dinner appointment.
Hey, Shelby?
Wake up. Eyes front.
[breathing heavily]
Mr. Shelby, you're trying to kill me,
were you?
Passing information...
[Jarvis] Fuck. He knows.
Where am I?
You are among the Odd Fellows.
Please count from ten to one.
Ah, fuck you.
Whatever else you might have forgotten
about last night,
remember this.
I am passing on information
to the Soviet Embassy
on the instruction of Section D.
It's part of a bigger picture.
You explain to the Russians
that you were mistaken about me,
and you apologize to me in front of them.
A threat on your sister
was evidently not enough.
You do as we say,
or we will take your son.
Hear this. We will take your son.
We can do it at any moment.
We have people in your life.
You will make your apology to me
tomorrow night,
and you will repair the damage
you've done.
[echoing] Or you will never
see your son again.
[groaning]
[door opens]
[Mary] Sir, I don't understand...
[Tommy panting]
I don't understand why,
as a former soldier yourself,
you have sacked all of the former
soldiers on the staff.
It means there is only one man
left in the household.
Mary, I want it so that
Charles is never left on his own.
Understood?
Sir, I should call a doctor.
There will be some men coming.
Coming down from Birmingham.
And you put them up here in the house.
You put them in the front and back of
the house, you feed them, and you...
Why are they needed, sir?
I brought a cursed sapphire
into this house, Mary.
And now, I'm paying for it.
And I don't know what to expect.
But neither do my enemies.
Tell David to bring the car around.
I need to go to London.
-Sir...
-And get me some tea, Mary.
Yes, sir.
[door opens]
-[phone clicks]
-[Arthur on phone] Hello?
-Yes, Arthur.
-Tommy?
They want the robbery to be sabotaged.
They don't give a fuck who gets hurt.
Are you okay, Tommy?
-It's a bigger picture now.
-What...
Did John make a list?
Speak clearer, Tom.
I said did John make a list?
John-Boy! John!
Right.
Gypsies and kin only. Yeah.
Good.
Tommy, can I ask you why?
Tommy?
[phone ringing]
No, Karl. I told you.
Go on and play in there.
Hello?
[sighs] Ada, it's me. It's Tommy.
Ada, I need you to...
I need you to speak
to one of your comrades
and get me a meeting
with someone from the Soviet Embassy.
Tonight.
Your place, 10:00 p.m.
[retching]
It seems that Mr. Shelby
was given bad information by an informant
who was also in contact
with the underwriter,
who, as we know,
is in the pocket of the Soviets.
-Wine, Tatiana?
-A little.
Bad girl.
[sniffing]
[door opens]
[door closes]
[sniffles]
[Tommy] Sorry I'm late. I, uh...
There was a body on the line.
[clears throat]
Drink, Mr. Shelby?
No, thank you.
It was drink that caused
half this trouble.
I have come here to apologize.
I have already explained
that you now realize
that your absurd allegation against me
was false.
Indeed.
[Hughes] And that your base nature
made you rash.
[sniffles]
And that now, once again,
our plan is back on track.
When a child in my care commits a sin,
first of all, he confesses,
as you just did.
And then,
I instruct him to perform penance
in a manner of my choosing.
As a child, you went to church?
Yes.
[Hughes] Do you remember
the Act of Contrition?
Good.
Do you remember
the words of the Act of Contrition?
[clears throat] Yes.
As your penance,
I would like you to recite it now,
in the presence of our associates.
[door opens]
Go away.
[Tommy clears throat]
[door closes]
Uh...
Oh, my God,
I am heartily sorry for having--
[Hughes] Instead of "God," say my name.
Since it was me you offended
with your false allegation.
Father Hughes, I am heartily sorry
for having offended you,
because of your just punishment,
but most of all, because they offend you.
Father Hughes, who art all good
and deserving of my love,
[sighs]
I firmly resolve to...
With the help of your grace,
to sin no more
and to avoid all near occasions of sin.
Mmm.
Very good. Thank you.
Amen.
[sighs]
And now that we are
a united band once more,
perhaps we could order some food.
I'm sorry. I am not feeling well.
I have to go. Good night.
Mr. Shelby...
[sniffling]
My God, Tommy.
-Are they here?
-Yeah.
-Do you have cocaine?
-No.
-[sighs]
-Tommy.
Uh, Tommy, this is the Special Adviser
to the Soviet Consul.
Members of the British establishment
and exiled White Russians
are planning to rob armored cars
from a factory in Birmingham.
We know about the robbery.
We have an informant.
No, your informant is working for them.
They want you to know about the robbery.
[speaking Russian]
Your informant is working for them.
They want you to know about the robbery.
[in English] Your informant
is working to their instruction.
[speaking Russian]
Your informant is working
to their instructions.
[in English]
Why would they want us to know?
They want you to...
They want you to stop the robbery.
They want you to commit a violent act
on British soil.
Tommy, do you want water?
A violent act on British...
[Dimitri speaking Russian]
...violent acts on British soil.
[sighs]
[in English] To force
the British government
to break off diplomatic relations.
[Dimitri speaking Russian]
To force the government
to break diplomatic relations.
[sniffles] That's the game.
The robbery in Birmingham
is just the bait.
[Dimitri speaking Russian]
Birmingham robbery is purely bait.
[in English] Why are you telling us this?
Because my family are the ones
who will be sacrificed
if you decide to blow up the train.
[Dimitri speaking Russian]
Because my family would be killed
if you decide to blow up the train.
[in English] The Consul wants to know
who you are.
He's Tommy Shelby.
You can take his word.
-[Tommy] Ada.
-Tommy...
Ada.
Okay.
[Ada grunting]
Stop, stop.
Ada, stop.
[grunts] Okay.
Drive me to a hospital, Ada.
If I'm not conscious when I get there,
tell them I have a fractured skull,
concussion and internal bleeding.
I think I may have hemorrhaged.
-Tommy.
-Ada, go on.
-Be quick because I can't see.
-Okay.
I can't fucking see.
[sobs] Okay. Okay.
Except for you, Dad.
I can see you.
♪ On a gathering storm comes ♪
♪ A tall handsome man ♪
♪ In a dusty black coat with ♪
♪ A red right hand ♪